LORETTA WANG

Los Angeles, CA (626) 321-2960 l.wang32@gmail.com lorettawang.github.io github.com/lorettawang linkedin.com/in/lorettawang

October 19, 2017

Dear Carrie Greiff, Laura Marks, Tracy Heverly, or Hiring Manager,

It is a pleasure to meet you! As a motivated, young (29 still counts as young, right?) professional strategist with over eight years of experience in diverse industries, I would love the chance to discuss the Product Manager position at Bluebeam. I am customer-centered, business-minded, and detail oriented with software engineer qualities. Companies I've worked for previously have run the scale from fledgling startups with fewer than five employees to well-established businesses with over 100 employees. In the past, I have also been hired for one role but invariably ended up managing multiple roles and wearing multiple hats. I am not afraid to adapt to the environment and have the ability to quickly fill different needs as they arise. As such, I'm well acquainted with the high-volume workloads and demands of fast-paced startup environments, and I have experience collaborating with cross-functional teams and managing a variety of different products from idea to launch. I am confident this position and company would be a great fit for me given my unique background and experience.

In 2014, fueled by my passion for creative expression and an entrepreneurial spirit, I started my own side business—The Social Booth Co.—a pop-up photo booth company dedicated to capturing life events in the most memorable way. Within 3 years of launching, I expanded my team to 4 people servicing multiple markets across the East and West coast. As a merchandising and product strategist, I helped create an e-commerce platform from the ground up that generated an additional \$50K+ in annual gross revenue. When I worked in risk management, I supervised multiple departments and analyzed an average of 70 new sales on a daily basis. In addition, I synthesized internal and external research, feedback, and analytics in order to drive iterative UX/UI improvements for our automated quoting platforms and created new organizational processes, workflows, policies, and procedures.

I also recently completed a full stack web development immersive, where I learned numerous programming languages and frameworks, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, and Node.js. During one of the projects, I was assigned to work with two other classmates and was declared the developer, as well as the scrum master after initiating the development process of our project. Without hesitation, I immediately created our pitch deck and the documentation of our backlog and MVP. During the five day sprint, I regularly created feature goals and made sure we completed them before leaving campus. Understanding the intersection of product development and software development can be difficult, but I believe I have the technical and non-technical skills needed to bridge the communication gap between teams.

In order to better understand Bluebeam and your product, I implemented user research methodologies and reached out to project engineers at Morley Builders and Crescent Heights to observe their use of Revu. The insight I gathered is the heavy emphasis on using "sessions" and "projects" to collaborate with their architects and contractors. They regularly upload different types of documents and need to create hyperlinks to link to relevant files. I also observed that creating comments and annotations is an action that is heavily used. One area I found both users did not use was the top section with the shapes, tools, and icons. Though these tools were rarely selected by the project engineers, my next step would be to contact architects and contractors to evaluate if their use of these shapes, tools, and icons are increased and how they regularly use them. When I asked about their general thought of Bluebeam and Revu, they stated it is a company and software that truly revolutionized their industry and provides a tremendous amount of efficiency to their daily workflow. Now, they wouldn't know how they can get any work done without Bluebeam!

Bluebeam is rapidly expanding and evolving, and I am thrilled at the possibility of growing with a company whose values align so closely with mine. I anticipate the opportunity to collaborate and help implement new ideas with a team of triathlon trainers (I'm trying to train for one before the big 3-0) and foodies (Nachos Jueves, oh yeah!). I have provided my resume for your consideration. I would love the chance to speak with you in further detail about the position and opportunity at Bluebeam. Thank you, and have a great one!

Sincerely, Loretta Wang

LORETTA WANG

Los Angeles, CA (626) 321-2960 l.wang32@gmail.com lorettawang.github.io github.com/lorettawang linkedin.com/in/lorettawang

SUMMARY

I am a business consultant in product strategy and developer with experience working in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, and Node.js. I have a background in risk analysis, business development, and digital marketing. Throughout my professional experience, my strengths have emerged in optimizing user-centered products, and creating efficient operational processes and workflows within various platforms

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Development Consultant | Independent Contractor | Los Angeles | 2015 - Present

- -Specialize working with fashion wholesale businesses in merchandising/product strategy: work with platforms to develop on technology and provide efficient inventory and shipping processes
- -Network, connect and establish relationships with East coast and West coast buyers; prepare emails, marketing material, presentations, estimates, and bids as necessary to meet specific buyer needs

Creative Director | The Social Booth Co | Los Angeles/New York | 2014 - Present

- -Shaping creative strategy for all projects and overseeing business operations
- -Responsible for all internal and external innovations including print collateral, interactive, web, events, packaging, graphics, and branding

Photographer | Independent Contractor | Los Angeles/New York | 2011 - 2016

- -Specialized in editorial, lifestyle and fashion photography, and events specific to client's needs
- -Executed the logistics of planning and scouting for shoot locations and photographed and color corrected on average 60 photographs per week. Portfolio of past work: www.lorettawangstudio.com

Risk Underwriter | R.V. Nuccio & Associates | Los Angeles, CA | 2014 - 2014

- -Worked on projects with a focus on collection and analysis of numerical data, trends, and statistics
- -Assisted with client applications, requests, technical support, and billing questions

VP, Risk Management | Athos Insurance Services | Pasadena, CA | 2013 - 2014

- -Supervised all lines of business and assisted with handling customer inquiries, technical support, billing questions
- -Ensured the accurate and on-time completion of all deadline-intensive projects

Risk/Account Manager | New Century Insurance Services | Alhambra, CA | 2009 - 2012

- -Used statistical analysis and compiled data to determine the risk factor of each applicant by the information provided
- -Provided additional aid and support to account executive and customer service representative departments

SKILLS

User Testing, Usability Testing, Trello, Git/GitHub, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, MERN Stack, Third Party APIs, Shopify, Squarespace, WordPress, Photoshop, Lightroom, Branding, Marketing, E-Commerce, and QuickBooks

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

- -Policy Manager BETA is an application for small business owners to input and manage business policy limits and was built in React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, and Mongoose within a 4-day sprint
- -PayUp is an application that keeps track of money owed and sends friendly text message reminders and was build in Node.js, Express, MongoDB, and Twilio integrated as a third-party API within a 5-day sprint
- -Linesheets is a B2B application for fashion wholesalers to sell their merchandise and was built using Ruby on Rails within a 5-day sprint
- -Connect Four is a game application that was built using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript within a 3-day sprint

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Immersive | General Assembly | 2017

B.A., Organizational & Interpersonal Communication | Cal State University, Fullerton | 2011

VOLUNTEER WORK

Community Development Volunteer | Adventures In Missions | South Africa + Swaziland | 2008 - 2009

-I took a year off and spent 10 months in Africa and taught English to elementary-level students, helped women find work + promoted sustainable development within their communities, and assisted with financial and operational tasks at AIM's Swaziland satellite office